# SABRINA CONTRERAS

+52 667 478 9034 @ sabriscon1307@gmail.com Culiacán, Sinaloa, México

SABRIS13 in Sabrina-Contreras

# **Summary**\_

Renewable Energy Engineer, specialized in alternative sources for electricity generation, and currently preparing to be a **Data Scientist** and **Front-End Developer**. Passionate about solving mysteries and enigmas through patterns, data, and graphics.

I'm also a self-taught and intuitive person in constant development, with experience in **data analysis**, **teamwork** and **communication** skills applied in education and research projects that meet energy needs.

### Skills\_\_\_\_\_

#### **SOFTSKILLS**

 Analytical Thinking • Adaptability • Time Management • Team work • Problem Solving • Communication

#### **HARD SKILLS**

- Python SQL HTML/CSS JavaScript
- Java Matlab GCP Git PowerBi R
- Tableau AutoCAD Microsoft Office

# Languages \_\_\_\_\_

## **SPANISH**

NATIVE

# ENGLISH

**TOEFL iBT**: 613

Voxy Profiency Achievement Certificate- Low Advance (C1)

#### **FRENCH**

Α1

## **Experience**

#### KUMON ASSISTANT | KUMON NORTH AMERICA, INC.

## Aug 2016 – Jul 2022

**♀** Sinaloa, Mexico

- Set up academic goals and individual lesson plans for each student to reach their academic level.
- Monitor the performance of at least 5 students at the same time to confirm or update expectations, needs, or type of instruction.
- Score student's Math, Reading and English homework.

# INTERN IN THE SUSTAINABILITY DEPARTMENT | COPPEL

**Aug** 2021 – Dec 2021

Sinaloa, Mexico

- Evaluation of the cost-benefits of the implementation of innovative technology in the company's CEDIs: Electric Mobility and Energy Storage.
- Report of the background and future of each technology, with a dimensioning of its application.

# **Education** \_\_\_\_

#### MASTER IN DATA SCIENCE/AI | DEV.F

max Apr 2022 – May 2023

 Implementation of analytical skills and tools (cleaning, analysis and visualization of data) to respond to business problems. Focused in: Data Wrangling, Data Visualization, Machine Learning, Deep learning y Machine Learning.

#### BENG. IN RENEWABLE ENERGY | TECNM

**Agus 2017 – Jan 2022** 

Sinaloa, Mexico

Gratuated with first class honors, GPA: 3.96

• Development and Evaluation of renewable energy projects focusing on its generation, transformation, storage, and management.

Extracurricular activities:

• Peer Tutoring in basic sciences courses for 2 semesters.

## **Courses & Certifications**

- Google Cloud Certificate: Associate Cloud Engineer
- Google Project Management Certificate: In progress
- Google Data Analytics Certificate
- Architecting with Google Compute Engine Certificacion
- ONE Oracle Next Education: Programming logic, Front-End and
- Diploma in **Financial Education**: CONDUSEF

# **Projects Volunteering**

- Hackathon BBVA 2022 CISCO Challenge
   Authentication for all: Multisensory Assessment Platform and Mobile App.
- Xignux-UDEM 2021 Award  $|\mathbf{1}^{st}place|$  Sustainable Climate Actions guide for Civil Society Organizations (CSOS).
- Casa Valentina for Children with Cancer IAP
   Supporting cancer patients by recycling 10,000 plastic caps and 50 kg of paper and carton.